<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>List on Chase Kanipe</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/list/</link>
    <description>Recent content in List on Chase Kanipe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Papers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-papers/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of my favorite papers.&#xA;Computer Science Exposing the Perils of Security Oblivious Energy Management Philosophy Todo Neuroscience Could a Neuroscientist Understand a Microprocessor? Funny What&amp;rsquo;s the Deal with Birds? A Demonstration of the Causal Power of Absences Sokal Hoax Long-Term Study of HRV Responses to Changes in the Solar and Geomagnetic Environment </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Words</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-words/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a reference list of words I like to include in essays.&#xA;Ameliorate, ascendant, ascertain, assertion, assessment, constituents, constitute, counterfactual, dispositive, eschaton, ephemeral, equilibrate, equivocate, exemplar, extemporaneous, harrowing, ideation, imperative, litany, litigate, obfuscate, obscure, opaque, parsimonious, recount, subvert, systematic, vexatious, voluminous</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-videos/</guid>
      <description>Computer Science Jim Keller on Microprocessors: An interview that discusses Jim&amp;#39;s career history, moore&amp;#39;s law, his hiring philosophy, and more.&#xA;Jim Keller on the future of computing: An interview that discusses Jim&amp;#39;s perspectives on the future of computing, AI, life, consciousness, and more.&#xA;GPT-4, ChatGPT, and the Future of AI: An interview with Sam Altman on OpenAI, GPT4, ChatGPT, DALL-E and many other leading AI technologies.&#xA;AI Safety: A discussion with Scott Aaronson on his work with OpenAI on ChatGPT, AI saftey, AI alignment, and various other topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-books/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of my favorite non-fiction books. I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to update this list as I discover new favories.&#xA;Computer Science The C Programming Language&#xA;The C&amp;#43;&amp;#43; Programming Language&#xA;The Rust Programming Language&#xA;Build Your Own Programming Language&#xA;Learn LLVM 12&#xA;Crafting Interpreters&#xA;Introduction to Static Analysis&#xA;Windows Kernel Programming&#xA;Modern x86 Assembly Language&#xA;Learn You a Haskell for Great Good&#xA;Cybersecurity Reversing: Secrets of Reverse Engineering&#xA;Hacking: The Art of Exploitation</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Quotes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/favorite-quotes/</guid>
      <description> The line between good and evil runs down the heart of every man You will die but C will live - Unknown professor </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
